so talking about construction
hmm rola strange develop development
similar to other was the fun it's M
Alvin I'm said Bhavana and bar baby
don't develop that which can be
developed so whatever development you're
doing develop it mmm Rahul of developing
development similar to earth Iker arisen
pressures that are pleasing or
displeasing will not keep obsessing the
mind Rahul it just does answer earth they
Rahul it just does answer earth they
throw clean things they talk dirty
things their excrement is a urine let's
go spits litter across
let's go flood the earth is not troubled
or worried or disgusted by this hmm in
just this way Rahula developed
development similar to earlier
developing and development similar to
arisen pressures the please emerges big
your contacts that are pleasing
releasing the freezing or displacing
will not keep obsessing the moment mmm
so I think we can just talk about that
one it's the same principle for all the
other development
so how would you start what do you think
say develop the development that is like
so establish your mind on
characteristics of Earth
what comes to mind when you hear that
the floor I'm sitting on
so the solid aspects in a way amove
about if you can sort of move in terms
of a particular representation of
solidity but it's in its core
characteristics is the quartet
characteristic is that it's solid so
what's the problem and why don't people
can just think of the solid earth and
become established mindfulness upon that
establish the mind on the lofty state
why why is it so hard to do that and
what is it that always results in
conceiving what is the necessary basis
for conceiving which is why people when
they think about it
the can established in mind because
they're basically conceiving not seeing
that their perceptions of birth depend
on earth yeah so the only reason people
can't establish their mind upon earth or
upon walls that open fire is because
they put themselves first that's it
so practically speaking here you are
thinking about it and you might be
clarifying the characteristics of Earth
and being very clear on this and even
like visual that's like visualizations
that's why they have big nonsense yes
when it comes to military practice it's
good I am visualizing this and somehow the
I am visualizing this and somehow the
content of your visualization will make
you mind establish know the right order
can only make her mind established so
the right order being in my perception
of it in my thoughts of the perception
of Earth I am second to that it's not
the result of me thinking it I can only
think it because I'm already within it
so funnily enough you just say
visualization in themselves
visualizations may not be wrong as long
as you understand what visualizations in
themselves are just that's what I mean
yeah so that visualizations they're
dependent on oh yeah of course
but see practice of visualization is
something you are doing I am visualizing
this and I'm imagining this and the
placing that first annual you pacing
yourself first
yeah you always place yourself first and
that's why the mind will not be
established so that's why you should be
as in that which is you so to speak be
like and the only way that you can be
like birth is to discern within you yeah
to discern earth as a necessary
container for you yeah so to discern
that presence of that solid aspect water
has to fire aspect area doesn't matter
Oh discern that phenomenon as you are
within it yeah so that's how you start
by taking in a correctly in that sense
and then yes so now are you are taking
enough and look doesn't care what
rubbish is thrown object you don't care
what words are thrown at you like you
cannot care even if your mind wants to
care he cannot step outside of the
correctly established context of Earth
is first and then any care that you have
about what said or what you got or what
you didn't get is within that context
which means it's no care at all but it
is it's it's actually just comes down to
establishing the context see you can oh
this is the context now this is what you
are attending and now there is a context
to that whole thing and that's which you
want to discern earth water fire on a or
any other casino or any other practice
of establishment of mind be jhanas or
brahma vihara it's always the same
principle
establish yourself on earth it's the
characteristics of Earth you're not
painting dirt rocks is it yeah you are
still maintaining the order today you
are first it's implicit even if you
don't necessarily think but you are
conceiving this this is a this is a
visitor do you want to discern the
characteristics of the earth that can be
solid indifferent immobile and then that
thought is a valid thought that
visualization is a valid visualization
there's no problem is but the problem is
if if you maintain the wrong order on
account of it or you correct the wrong
water so once you establish your
thoughts which are in the beginning
abstract thoughts of Earth that's fine
now allow those abstract thoughts to
endure and you see yourself within them
not their product of view that's the
whole point
and then they cease to be abstract
because of its content so that thought
that I have a worth is the only earth I
know that's your starting point but now
within that thought about your sense of
I am your center stuff you want to see
dependent on that thought of Earth as in
that thought of Earth is close to what
Earth is and not close to it you are
thinking in terms of my thought so
that's when your own thoughts are seeing
correctly representing the state of
things they you are affected by you but
in it that's what it says that whatever
pressure is M felt on account of
whatever is within pleasant unpleasant
neutral you won't be pressuring you
because you have basically abandoned the
whole picture through maintained in the
context that is indifferent uh no noble
you can own the element of Earth it's
inconceivable and now the mind starts to
establish that seeing its own sense of
ownership its own sense of self its own
like me the world fully dependent within
this thought that represents earth this
thought of Earth is actually more
elemental than anything I do within it
so all you need to do is maintain the
context of their thought and you are
basically practicing establishing upon
yourself I still share mine upon the perception
I still share mine upon the perception
well yeah yeah sure but it's it's your
experience it's like the outlet there is
no more than I mean if you keep thinking
about what earth is yeah you're gonna be
thinking for over thought of it all baby
doesn't matter whether it is it's
whatever thoughts represents the earth
it's what is for me for me and that's
how it ceases to be abstract that and
that will become it will be more and
more accurate yeah it won't be actually
in the beginning but the principle will
be ahead so then you get to define that
which is sort of exemplified by the
offensive
so that's what dwelling on the
properties of Earth oh it doesn't care
if the rubbish is thrown it doesn't give
it up or destroy earth remains there
that solid aspect remains unchanged so
to speak even even the change is within
it but the change cannot really change
the solidity of it can only change the
form of that solidity between solidity
remains unchanged and during series can
you have your body without the solid
material is present is it conceivable
for you to experience of feelings
perceptions thoughts moods without this
solid probably being here it's
inconceivable and that solid body is
closer to the stone to the tree to the
dog to the to the bag to the stake than
it is to anything you think you are now
you can't stop thinking that you are
this so do that but you can certainly
stop entertaining the wrong order on
account of it so that's all these
contexts are useful only if you then put
yourself in the right place against it
so to speak not in itself just going
through the motions of visualizations
and somehow work will be magically done
for you all my worries phase whatever is
present simultaneously to that presence
there is this solid aspect of the body
present which is like the stone like the
branch like the tree yeah so the
emotional pressure remains and you are
not within it anymore
so it doesn't pressure you which means
it's not really crashing anymore
exactly so the pressure pleasing
displeasing is there but it cannot
obsess the mind
I think like
I think this is often used as their
color I think people people would often use
I think people people would often use
this as a teaching as an inspirational
kind of reflection uh quietly almost
yeah I will emulate there but the only
way to truly M&I that without
misconceiving it is to put yourself
against it as secular as dependent upon
it not as that which is responsible for
its origination to it simultaneously
there but second to it yeah that's
solidity that solid aspect you could
just do it on the body did you find the
solar that's big there you have solid SP
all over you so you start internal
you'll find it external it doesn't
matter the point is not to go further
and get the right solid ass but the
point is to start seeing the right order
the right context of your situation
based on that solid Esper so again if I
ask you do you have the body of a
certain form you don't need to stop and
think about if you already know yes of
course so allow that pool to endure
peripherally while you then see yourself
wanting this not one thing that thinking
this thinking that wanting to do this
and so on
within the context of that necessary
solid lump that needs to be present
there in order for you to want anything
see that body that's solid aspect comes
first yes comes first in the sense of is there
yes comes first in the sense of is there
is a container of everything you can
think including the solid aspect
so you can't step outside of it in as
much you cannot step outside of your
body in your senses like you can have
the solid aspects can be there even if
you're not thinking about them the sort
of solid aspect and I would stick to
this solid aspect then if you get the
sense of that then you can refine it to
deep water sort of fluid aspect but
they're a bit more refined and you
wouldn't find them left or right from
the solid you'll find it within the
solid it's not like this one two three
four I have to meet no you meet one you
made them all this space yeah but again
it's it's even more defined and then the
Atma the utmost refined one is the
consciousness let's in the Sutra
hibakusyas starts with the elements
start with perception in space and then
the conscience is the most refined one
but again it's always the same principle
so it's just if you have the capacity to
maintain this level of context
establishment in the sermon to the point
of your consciousness an infinite space
yeah that's absolutely great but the
problem is people already misconceive
the starting point so talking about
everything else is just gonna be like
information about everything which will
quite often result in uh okay that's
what this is that's what it says that's
what this is and you haven't established
anything yeah this is a right context
establish it all you're just having it
all only like abstract later layout and
and making sense of it over there
so these aspects are all these I guess
consciousness space firewater they all
share that those same characteristics of
just that imperturbability well they're
not on the same plane it's not like
these whole things share these
characteristics for you the first thing
the first framework the first container
is a solid within the solid you get to
design fluid within the solid within the
fluid you get to discern Airy and then
within that you get decent far not left
to right before or after
so that's why mean you want to resist
the temptation to go into the abstract
leaf figuring them all out making sense
of it and actually focus on okay no I'll
just be patient
I'll put these other three aside in the
same sense with the Germans and develop
the first establish your mind upon the
context of solidity that induces a
necessary basis for any experience that
it's currently occurring to you you know
I must stop this experience no I must
see beyond it I must see what is the
necessary basis so that I can finally
have space to not own this anymore but
you can own it as an act of will oh this
is not mind or that is yours your denial
of ownership is what you own but if you
see that does bother you
oh this is mine this is not mine it's
all under money something that's
inconceivably it's inconceivable to be
yours you cannot possibly conceive
container of Earth you can step outside
of it and own it you can't even
fantasies about it and when that becomes
clear any sense of ownership maintained
within the dependence of that context
you will have to fade it will not be the
ownership in the sense of I am the real
genuine owner it's like like the suit
that says you know borrowed jewel living
when you borrow the golden jewelry and
then you forget that you borrowed it and
you're enjoying the pleasures you get an
economy the admiration you get an
account or value you get confident and
they you know the real owner comes and
takes it away because you completely
lost perception to you
it was only bottle so you don't suffer
because you borrowed it or because you
lost you suffer because you thought you
owned it if you never forgot that it
will have to be taken away you will not
be surprised when it's taken away which
means you can't suffer when it's taken
away so that's the whole point you want
to undermine these gratuitous sense of
ownership of your own body of your own
life by seeing that it's owned by
something much greater that you cannot
even conceive only and that's how you
will remove any any dependence on their
body and their life so you can still use
it like you would the power of things
but they will not lead you to assume
that you are the owner master controller
create yeah that's right that's why it
automatically results in the India in
the view of our Towada and the ownership
you don't need to like on audit to
develop the wrong view no automatically
there is no beginning where the wrong
view was not manifested beforehand but
it shouldn't be there cuz you were never
the owner you could have never owned it
but you don't know that because I'm not
knowing that that's why you own it and
that's why you gonna get affected with
those things do not obey your master
your ownership your world when they
don't go the way you want them to be but
unless you find out the way to approve
the ownership you can't
that's why doesn't match the amount of
misfortune you might experience in life
the amount of loss you still never gonna
bandar not allowed on account of it
because you don't know thank you you
don't know how you don't know what to
see cuz all you see is me and everything
else that's all other hand sees as well
but the difference is our hand puts
everything else is a necessary container
for me which is now resulted in
completing all of ownership the Agena
doesn't put everything else as
the necessary condition for me he puts
it all the way around he puts himself at
us and that's it you can't change and I
think my point of view know the world
but you can certainly change what is
being prioritized that's so that the
sense restraint in the world would
constantly kind of keep reiterating that
you must not give in to desire and lust
because it's through that kind of
engagement with the world you maintain
the wrong order by removing the desire
and lost by not acting out of it you
release not perpetuate in the wrong
order and then you get to understand it
and when you do that there is no more
desire alas given to arrive